Nassau Bay Garden Club Records
University of Houston-Clear Lake Archives & Special Collections
Nassau Bay Garden Club Records
1971-2006
1980-2000
Nassau Bay Garden Club
2014-0002
Eight 5" document cases and ten oversized scrapbook boxes (10 linear feet)
University of Houston-Clear Lake Archives & Special Collections
The Nassau Bay Garden Club collection documents the organizational records of the Nassau Bay Garden Club from 1964-2000.
Administrative History
The Nassau Bay Garden Club was chartered in 1964 and is one of the oldest organizations in Nassau Bay, TX. The first year saw twenty-three charter members and the adoption of the pansy as its club flower.
During the 1965-66 year, the Club was accepted into the Houston Federation of Garden Clubs, Inc. and the Yard of the Month awards and first flower shows were instituted. Other early years saw the beginning of the annual Christmas Tour of Homes, judging of outdoor Christmas lights, and the planting and lighting of a memorial Christmas tree in honor of astronaut Roger Chaffee, who died in the Apollo 1 spacecraft fire in 1967.
Other projects have included Arbor Day tree plantings, beautification of NASA Rd. 1, donations of litter barrels and money, and plantings of other shrubs and flowers at Nassau Bay establishments.
The Club elects and appoints board and committee officers every year and membership is open to any resident of the City of Nassau Bay.
Scope and Contents of the Records
This is a collection of the records of the Nassau Bay Garden Club, located in Nassau Bay, Texas. Nassau Bay is situated across from the Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas.
Types of records include historical documents, meeting minutes, treasurer reports and ledgers, tax information, membership rosters, reports of various committees and Club presidents, correspondence, and project files, including those of the Yard of the Month competition and fundraisers. Also included are the Club newsletters Bloomin' Notes and Blossoming Notes, as well as scrapbooks dating back to 1971 and culminating with the year 1999. The scrapbooks contain fliers, clippings, artwork, and photos documenting the activities of the Garden Club
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into thirteen series and folders are arranged by date. The Club's original scrapbooks are housed in large oversized boxes at the end of the collection.
Access Restrictions
Unrestricted
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Houston Federation of Garden Clubs, Inc.; Nassau Bay Garden Club
Subjects
Newsletters; Scrapbooks
Places
Nassau Bay, Texas
Separated Material
The 1977-78 scrapbook came to the UHCL Archives after sustaining water-damage and contained mold. It has been scanned and removed from the collection and is available within the collection as a .pdf.
Acquisition Information
Nassau Bay Garden Club members Ann Davidson and Geraldine Higgs contacted the UHCL Archives to discuss the Garden Club records housed in a self-storage storage facility on Kirby Road near NASA Rd. 1. On October 21, 2010, UHCL archivist Shelly Kelly met the two ladies at the storage unit and seven boxes of records were picked up and brought to UHCL for preservation.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Series I: Historical Features
  - Bylaws Texas Garden Clubs, Inc., 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Honor Roll Club Rating Worksheet, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Incorporation Papers, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Parliamentarian Budget, undated; 1986,; 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series II: Budget
  - Budget and Treasurer Report, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Budget (Proposed), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Budget and Audit, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Budget, Audit, Treasurer's Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Budget, Ledger, Treasurer's Report, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Budget, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Budget, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Budget and Ledger, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Budget, Ledger, Audit, and Treasurer's Reports, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Budget (Proposed) and Ledger, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Budget (Proposed), Ledger, and Treasurer's Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Budget and Ledger, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Budget and Treasurer's Reports, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Budget, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Budget, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Budget, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Financial Report (includes computer diskette), 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Fundraiser Report, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Budget and Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Budget Review, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Actual Budget, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Budget, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Budget Review and Audit, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Budget and Proposed Budget, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Budget and Proposed Budget, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Combined Register Report and Proposed Budget, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Proposed Budget, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Treasurer's Ledger Sheets, 1978-1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Treasurer's Ledger Sheets, 1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Series III: Correspondence
  - Correspondence-General, 1980-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence-General, 1980-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence-General, 1993-1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence-General, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence-General, 2001-2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence-General, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Leaving Houston Federation of Garden Clubs, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Postcards and Mailing Labels, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Meetings
  - Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Minutes/Agendas, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Minutes/Agendas, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1989-1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2000-2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Series V: Memberships
  - Membership Lists, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Membership Lists, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Membership Lists 2003, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Texas Garden Club Roster, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Series VI: Publications
  - Newsletters, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Series VII: President's Notebook
  - President's Notebook-Adele McCoy, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - President's Notebook-Sally Underwood, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - President's Notebook-Sally Underwood, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - President's Notebook-Sue Warters, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - President's Notebook-Lynne Wilson, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - President's Notebook-Lucille Redmond, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - President's Notebook-Lucille Redmond, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - President's Notebook-Ann Gay, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - President's Notebook-Ann Gay, 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - President's Notebook-Ann Gay, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - President's Notebook-Ann Gay, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Series VIII: Project Files-Yard of the Month
  - Yard of the Month, 1978-1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Yard of the Month, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Home Beautification Committee, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Home Beautification Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Series IX: Fundraising
  - Christmas Tour, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Financial Projects, 1991-1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fundraising Project Notebook, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fundraising Project, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Fundraising Project Notebook, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Fundraising Project, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Fundraising Project 2004 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Series X: Reports
  - Committee and Officers Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Committee and Officers Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Committee Reports, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Committee Reports, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Committee Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Committee Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Committee Reports, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Executive Board Meeting, 1987 February 19 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - President's Reports, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - President's Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - President's Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - President's Reports, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - President's Reports, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - President's Reports, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - President's Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 4 President's Reports, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - President's Reports, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - President's Reports, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - President's Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - President's Reports, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - President's Reports, 2005-2006 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Series XI: Taxes
  - Internal Revenue Service, 1993-2000 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Internal Revenue Service 2001-2006 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Series XII: Miscellaneous
  - Clippings/Miscellaneous, 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Clippings/Miscellaneous, 1995-1998 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Clippings/Miscellaneous, 2002-2005 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Series XIV: Scrapbooks
  - Nassau Bay Garden Club Scrapbook, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    Note: This scrapbook sustained water and mold damage before coming to the archives. The original has been scanned and removed from the collection. A copy has been placed here and is also available as a .pdf file
- Series XV: Scrapbooks-Oversized boxes
  - Nassau Bay Garden Club Scrapbook, 1971-1972 (Box 9)
  - Nassau Bay Garden Club Scrapbook, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Nassau Bay Garden Club Scrapbook, 1974-1975 (Box 11)
  - Nassau Bay Garden Club Scrapbook, 1979-1980; 1984-1985 (Box 12)
  - Nassau Bay Garden Club Scrapbook, 1992-1993 (Box 13)
  - Nassau Bay Garden Club Scrapbook, 1993-1994 (Box 14)
  - Nassau Bay Garden Club Scrapbook, 1994-1995 (Box 15)
  - Nassau Bay Garden Club Scrapbook, 1996-1997 (Box 16)
  - Nassau Bay Garden Club Scrapbook, 1997-1998 (Box 17)
  - Nassau Bay Garden Club Scrapbook, 1998-1999 (Box 18)